Prasenjit Pawar

♥ Aurangabad, Maharashtra, India ■ prasenjitpawar22@gmail.com □ 8669106099 📠 https://www.linkedin.com/in/prasenjit-pawar-2b378b77 🕳 https://prasen.co.in/

SUMMARY

Experienced software engineer with 1 year of experience in frontend and backend development. Proficient in multiple programming languages and able to quickly learn new technologies. Demonstrated ability to solve technical problems and develop software solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Capgemini

April 2022 - Present, Mumbai, India

- · Implemented scalable REST APIs on enterprise-level microservices.
- · Became AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner and added unit/integration test cases which increased the code coverage up to 70%, CI/CD, pull request, and code review.
- · Tech Stack C#, .NET, Azure, MSSQL, Jira, Git, Docker.

MERN Stack Intern

Banao Technologies

March 2022 - April 2022, Bangalore, India

- · Designed and implemented responsive mobile applications for both user android and iOS using React Native and Expo technologies.
- · Added functionalities for web users by making them more user-friendly and responsive using React and CSS Frameworks.
- · Tech Stack React, React Native, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, MongoDB, Nodejs.

PROJECTS

Distributed Order Management (DOM)

Capgemini · November 2022 - Present

- · The Distributed Order Management (DOM) system is a custom-built solution aimed at optimizing and streamlining order management processes.
- · By leveraging a microservices architecture, DOM enables efficient handling and coordination of orders, resulting in improved operational efficiency and cost-effectiveness.
- · With a tech stack comprising .NET Core for the backend, React.js for the front end, and Azure for cloud hosting, DOM provides a robust and scalable platform for effective order management.

Link?

Personal Project · June 2023 - June 2023

- Developed and launched a personal side project called "Link3" Link-a-Bio, a web application that allows users to create a personalized profile with links and profile pictures.
- · Implemented a user-friendly interface for users to easily add, edit, and manage their profile links and upload profile pictures, enhancing the customization options available.
- · Utilized modern web development technologies such as Next.js, Tailwind CSS, and Trpc to create an intuitive and visually appealing user experience.
- · Project Link: https://link3-pi.vercel.app/

Resume Builder

Personal Project • February 2023 -April 2023

- $\cdot \text{A simple tool to build a resume, integrated Clerk for authentication, one-click download as PDF functionality}.$
- · Tech stack: Express.js, React.js, MongoDB.
- · Link: https://resume-builder-frontend-ten.vercel.app/

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering

Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar Marathwada Technological University · Maharashtra, India · 2021 · 7.8

Diploma in Computer Engineering

Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education · Maharashtra, India · 2018 · 7.3

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Amazon · 2022

The AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner offers a foundational understanding of AWS Cloud concepts, services, and terminology

SKILLS

Frontend: Next.js, React.js.

Backend: Express.js, .NET Core.

MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Docker, Jira